Jakub Dejworek

jakubdejworek@gmail.com | +1 (847)-873-3795 | https://jakubdejworek.vercel.app/

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

A multi-talented individual who is capable of delivering a meaningful impact in Frontend Development including UI and UX. He is adept in several web technologies including React, TypeScript and NextJS. With a strong motivation for self-improvement, he takes the time to research and teach himself new technologies such as Tailwind and React Native. He is able to confidently tackle challenges and learn new skills quickly, especially when developing a website from the ground up, for example an image filter and an email system were systems he needed to learn about on the fly and was able to implement successfully. Jakub also became the development team leader for the migration of an Android app from XML to Jetpack Compose.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

J.D. Exterior - Prospect Heights, IL

2023 - PRESENT

A Chicago area-based home improvement company specializing in general remodeling

Website Developer - Created and managed all areas of the company's website including brand identity and UI/UX design using Figma

- Developed full-stack web application using Next.js, TypeScript, resulting in 40% increase in client inquiries
- Implemented automated email system using Next.Email and Resend, resulting in an increase in leads by 10%
- Setup and deployed scalable image storage solution using Supabase, which managed all project photos, allowing clients to view other projects in their free time and improved customer satisfaction
- Designed and implemented custom components as well as various animations and notifications, improving functionality of the site while staying consistent with the brand Identity

Shure - Niles, IL

MAY 2023 - AUGUST 2023

A \$750M world leader in the design, manufacture, and distribution of audio products, microphones, headphones including phonograph cartridges, signal processors, and personal monitor systems.

Android Software Developer Intern

Migrated an Android app from the traditional Android view system to Jetpack Compose

- Led migration of legacy Android app from XML to Jetpack Compose, reducing the amount of code needed (ex. screens with RecyclerView) and improving maintainability
- Analyzed and converted 10+ XML layouts while preserving 100% functionality, while also adding responsiveness to align more closely to optimal modern design practices, resulting in an improvement for user experience
- Implemented automated testing for UI components, leading to fewer bug reports and increasing overall productivity for the development team

Android Software Developer Intern

2021 - 2022

Created and implemented the UI flow process for a microphone controller app

- Designed and implemented user interfaces for an Android application following Material Design guidelines, this was to increase efficiency in the development process and to stay consistent with the practices of developers on the same team
- Collaborated with 2 product managers and 1 UX designer to translate requirements into 15+ reusable UI components
- Developed custom animations and interactive layouts, which led to an improvement of the UI and user experience
- Maintained compatibility across different Android versions and device types

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: React, Next.js, TypeScript, CSS/Tailwind **Mobile:** Android (Jetpack Compose, XML), React Native

Backend: Node.js

Database: SQL, Single Store, Supabase

Tools & Others: Git, Figma

In Progress: React Native, Motion (Framer Motion), Python

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS IN CHICAGO (UIC) - CHICAGO, IL

2019 - 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BSCS)